Thank you.
And the manifest presence of God's spirit is amazing.
It makes preachers so much easier.
So today, I want to talk about a real simple topic.
It is an incredibly deep topic.
And just like last week, we talked about the Word and the importance of God's Word and how we rely on God's Word, how we submit to it, obey it, pray it, listen to it, all that kind of stuff.
And there is just so much to cover up there.
And we did a flyover.
We're going to go do a flyover again of an incredibly deep, profound topic.
It's essential in Christianity.
And I just have to confess that I'm going to do a bit of a flyover.
I'm going to take five different passages from very different perspectives and tie them all into one topic, and it's the topic of salvation.
So bear with me as I do this.
It's part of the agreement that we're going to ask people to enter into who want to be charter members at this church.
It's important that you believe in the Word of God, and we did that last time.
You submit to the Word of God.
But there's also this very real sense that the people who get to make decisions here, we want to make sure they're saved.
It's important to us that they know Jesus when they're listening to Jesus.
It's not matter.
So the commonest statement is, as a member of the church, I accept the Bible as the Word of God, which is revealed in the way of salvation.
In the guides of faith and Christian living, we talked about that last week, this week, I confess to a personal experience of God's moving grace in my life.
And with the help of the Holy Spirit, I intend to reject sin and to live a holy life devoted to the example and teaching of Christ.
So I had a really good friend in Wisconsin who was my board chair, really smart side.
He was also a board chair.
He was a VP of finance at IBM.
Very well-to-do religion and incredibly well-to-do neighborhood.
Very self-sufficient folks.
Very accomplished people with his neighbors all over.
And he constantly tried to do Bible studies in his neighborhood.
And he's very likable.
So he got to know everyone.
And they want to hang out with Gary and Joanne.
And he's a straight couple.
But he said, you know, my biggest problem in my neighborhood is not getting someone saved.
It's getting them lost.
And that's what we all thought they had together.
And this realization that I need a Savior.
What did it begin with?
The Scripture that was read, that Luke passage.
It'll be interesting when we get to that parable that Jesus tells.
Because you can look at those two.
And just from the parable, which one do you think was living a better holy life?
And which one got justified?
I appreciate Gary's honesty.
So, the first passage I'd like to look at.
Then the Lord took the man.
You know, it's the song, right?
Right?
Genesis.
Then the Lord took the man and put him into the garden of Eden,
which masturbated and keep him.
And the Lord God commanded the man, saying,
From any tree of the garden you may eat freely.
But from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, you shall not eat.
And here's the question.
For in the day that you eat from it, you will surely die.
And you know the story, right?
Then he puts him in the fridge, and he ends up making the woman well,
and they're together, and she succeeds, and she eats, and she gives it to him,
and he eats.
And so, here's my question.
What's up?
Because it said, the day that you eat of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil,
the day, you shall surely die.
But then we read about their life that went on for a long time after that moment.
Well, what's up?
Here it is.
The spirit of God.
They were in perfect communion with God.
Prior to the fall, they had a relationship with God that was unfettered.
It was, it was wonderful.
And that part of the human, the spirit of a man, the spirit of a woman,
the day that they chose to rebel and eat, it died.
It's why later in the New Testament we talk about things like you must be born again.
Because that which can use with God, because of sin, the wages of sin is death.
It's death.
And so, it didn't get a physical death, but it enacted an absolute death of their sin.
Folks, we come into the world needing a savior to reconnect that which is dead in us.
Make it alive that we can communicate with God.
It's that simple.
I do understand that we are image bearers,
and so when his word is preached because we're image bearers,
we're made in the image of God, we can harmonize, we can resonate,
you can, you can realize that it's God speaking,
but God has to make alive in you that which he originally put in humans
to be in communion with them.
Let's do it.
That's salvation, folks.
I empathize with Jerry because I know that a lot of people, our culture, our world, our environment,
our concept teaches us that, well, we're basically good.
And if we just learn a little more, we'll be good together.
And usually what we end up doing is we compare ourselves to someone who is a little or a lot worse than us,
and we say, oh, yeah, I know, I'm perfect, but look at them.
I'm better than them.
And it's funny because often when you look at them,
they might seem more moral, better than me in four or five areas.
I just pick on the one that shows me on my eyes to show that I'm better.
Well, here's the reality.
I'm going to ask you an ethical question here.
Which is worse if I step on an axe or I publicly shame a three-year-old repeatedly?
Which is worse?
Good for the obvious.
What's that?
B.
Yes, I mean, if I publicly shame a child on a regular basis,
that's like, I mean, forgiveness for them.
I need to talk to you.
I don't know, maybe they just take out the word you say, you know,
because you don't do that.
But if I step on the ant, I kill it.
Wait, isn't killing worse than shaming?
What's the difference?
Well, here's the difference.
That three-year-old is infinitely more valuable than that ant.
That three-year-old is an image-based.
It's a human.
And violently, I'm serious.
An ant is here, and that human is over here.
No, I kill the ant.
Maybe that's not good.
I don't know.
It depends on what you think God is.
But over here, standing in a trial, we go,
but you don't do it.
You just don't try it because the child is worth so much more than that is.
And here's my question.
If you end here on this war spill,
and the child is here to lose God,
and you drive, like, out in the green room on the war spill,
God is of infinite value and worth.
That's why we can't compare what I do to you or what I do to you.
When we deal with God,
I think why taking the Lord's name and being is such a problem.
It was a problem.
So, I think we need to begin with the sense that I'm broken.
I'm fallen.
Often when I serve the Lord as people,
and people want to argue with me about whether they're basically good
and people are basically good,
I generally do this thing over and over again.
And I've never let anybody do anything other than be quiet and go,
that's what it is.
If I take an honest look at my heart,
I feel ugly.
Now, I'm too proficient in hiding it from one of you.
I'm not as proficient in hiding it from my wife.
I'm less proficient in hiding it from my children.
Children, I'm not as proficient.
If I take an honest look at my heart,
I think I'm ugly.
We are fallen.
We are broken.
We are sinful.
And we are desperately in need of the city.
If you don't need a Savior,
then Jesus is passive like force.
We need a Savior.
You ever heard the song,
Jesus loves you just the way you are?
Yes.
So, that is both true and a distortion.
It is true that Jesus loves you just the way you are.
He does.
He loves you.
He loves you just the way you are.
You're a murderer.
He loves you.
You're a pedophile.
You're a thief.
He loves you.
But he doesn't like that about you.
You hear the difference?
When he says Jesus loves you just the way you are,
it doesn't mean he loves just the way you are.
He loves you.
But there was a phrase that they used to hear a long time ago,
we love you just as you are,
but we love you too much to leave you that way.
God loves you just as you are.
He loves you,
but he doesn't like some of you.
And so, he sent us to you here to forbid you,
to give you authority and power to say no to that stuff.
It's called redemption.
It's called justification.
It's called sanctification.
It's salvation.
It's us.
We're saved.
We're being saved.
We will be saved.
Okay.
Second verse I'd like to look at if I can.
This one's a little longer.
We read it today,
but I want to read through it again.
And he also told this parable to some people
who trusted in themselves
that they were righteous
and viewed others with contempt.
Two men went up into the temple to pray.
The one of Pharisees.
By the way,
the Pharisees were the morally upright individuals of the day.
I think it's a bad rap in the Scriptures,
but there were some,
Nicodemus was a pretty good rap.
And there were some good Pharisees up there.
And they were so nice.
They were walking out.
Not all of them,
but, you know,
there's some good Christians here.
Not all of them.
Okay.
Don't meddle now.
The Pharisees stood and was praying this to himself.
God,
I thank you that I am not like other people.
Windlers.
I'm not swindlers.
I don't swindlers.
Unjust.
That's not me.
Adulterers.
I don't do adultery.
Or even like this press cholesterol.
Most experiences,
most people in America
don't like Catholic collectors too much.
And let me tell you,
it was a lot worse in that context.
But we won't do any of that.
This is a historical study worth itself
any other time.
I fast twice a week.
By the way,
that's better than I do.
Anyone here fast twice a week?
You know,
I can do some.
I take lives of all that I get.
But the Catholic collectors,
the Catholic collectors
he couldn't even get close
to where he believed God was.
He couldn't even approach the people.
The Catholic collector was so aware
of how far of sorts he fell
from the glory of God,
the goodness of God.
He saw God on that stairway over there
that he had violated.
I can't even get close.
I can't get close.
I can't look up.
And he had one plea.
Have mercy.
Now, we read it,
you know,
he beat his dress
and said,
have mercy on me,
oh Lord.
But we can all set up.
And we get to get the emotion
of this person
who cannot approach God,
cannot even look up to heaven,
probably does some of the things
or has done
or is doing some of the things
that that Pharisee says,
I don't do.
I'm probably not doing
some of the things
the Pharisee said,
I do.
He said,
I can't.
I don't.
I fall for it.
But the task will up to you.
Bending some distance away
was even unruly
to lift up the body
to heaven.
For even his grace
in the name of God
is merciful to me this man.
I tell you,
Jesus says,
this man
went to his hands
just to find
greater than the other.
For everyone
who exalts himself
will be humbled
and who humbles himself
will be exalted.
Those who trust
their own righteousness
are farthest
from the kingdom of God
according to Jesus.
I need a savior.
We need a savior.
I'm going to say,
this world
is not a place.
Of course you do.
30 years ago
kind of introduced
the concept
that he discovered
while he was
doing his work
in India.
You do know
different cultures
do things differently.
And I'm not just
talking about
how they,
you know,
eat.
Whether it's
chopsticks
or fingering
or sport fork
or whatever.
Have any of you
ever been somewhere
where someone
just eats
their curry
with their hand?
And I was in India
and there's this lady
this beautiful story.
I mean,
it's just a beautiful
colorful dress
and she's talking to me.
It's a memory
world release
for what I've done
there in India.
And she's talking
and we're all outside
and there's this curry dish
she's just flopping
chicken with yellow
sauce over rice
and she's picking it up
and she's eating it
and while we're talking
all I can see
is this stuff
dripping off her hands.
I'm trying to look
in her eyes
and I keep looking
at her hands,
you know.
Because it's,
oh,
it's weird for me
and I finally remember
them,
you know,
I learned,
first of all,
you don't worry
about it.
You just pick it up
and when you get
floppy,
so do it right
before you've got
an napkin form.
I don't know
how many people
sell it
really pretty though.
I have no clue
because I'd be doing
one of these,
you know.
So culture,
do you agree?
Cultures are different
even beyond a mess.
Let me give you
another illustration
because I think
it's important
when we accept
this from us.
You know the
prodigal son story?
Well,
most of you do.
If you don't,
I can tell you afterwards.
So,
and I think I've used
this before
but I'm not sure
so I'll do it again.
A researcher
by the name of
John Hall
went to evangelical
castings
in the old USSR
and then in
sub-Saharan Africa
North America
and he asked
one question.
When the prodigal son
who left his father's
house with his
stuff,
when he got out there
and things got really bad
he ended up
in the pigsty
wanting to eat
the stuff
and was feeding
the pigs.
And John Hall
asked these
clergy,
these religious folks
why did he end up
in the pigsty?
And in North America
pretty much everyone
said,
well it's really obvious,
read the text,
he wondered
finder in his wealth.
He had nothing left
and was the only job
he could get.
He was irresponsible.
When they asked
those in the USSR
they said,
well it's going to
collect freedom.
It's because there was
a famine in the women.
You see in the old USSR
there wasn't a lot
of personal autonomy
and personal control
at that point.
They told you
where to live,
they told you
what job you had,
how long you had it,
how long you worked,
what you did
was what you got
from that job,
what you gave,
what you got to do.
And so then
the circumstances
really mattered.
And then they asked
these African questions,
why are you
in the three days?
And they said,
oh it's in the 12th,
read it.
It's because no one
gives him anything
to eat.
Here's the deal folks,
go home and read it.
Because all three
are given equal weight
in the text.
But we all see it
through our lives.
So, just get that
as I talk about
Paul Hebert.
Paul Hebert is now
in India,
he was then,
and he's noticing
the chosen elders
of my name
and he has no clue
how they're choosing
their elders.
And he's,
what's the criteria?
He can't figure out
what's the criteria.
And he asked people
and they couldn't even
understand the question.
And then he's
not a stuntman
that I think
is really helpful
and some of you
are probably familiar
with it because
it's become
popularized.
But he talked
about the
bounded space.
That we in
North America
tend to categorize
things by a
bounded space.
What do I mean
by that?
Okay, what is
an apple?
Well, an apple
is the mature,
round fruit
of the lowest
domestical planet.
That's what it is.
And you can have
a massive glass waffle,
you can have
a green snake apple,
a baking apple,
you can have
an Indian apple.
I mean,
they can be
kind of reddish,
yellow-green,
they can be
all red,
they can be mussel,
they can be crisp.
But here's the problem.
They can also be rotten.
And they're still
an apple.
And the problem
is that we
in the West
tend to take
this cultural
tendency
to categorize
things
by the
boundaries
of it
and we
bring that
to the church.
And I'm not
saying it's wrong,
I'm just saying
that it's
insufficient.
Because what we
do then
is say,
okay,
those who are
Christians
are those who
have
these beliefs
and they have
these behaviors.
The problem
is that we
got lots
of denominations
because we
don't all agree
on what are
the beliefs
and what are
the behaviors.
We disagree
over those
things and we
argue over
those things.
What gets
you in and
what gets
you asked?
By the way,
this was the
approach of
the Pharisees
to righteousness.
Now,
I'm not saying
it's wrong.
It's kind of
funny when
Paul Hebert
first presented
this,
a young
dealing person
with that
the person
who wrote
the response
keeper
to Hebert
and told
him why
he was
all wrong
and he
responded back
to our
things and
said,
everything
he said
is great
if I'm
teaching and
teaching in
India because
they need
to hear about
the balance
of the
center
over in
India,
but here
in America
we're so
freaking
bound to
set.
We need
to see
the
alternative.
We need
to see
the corrective.
We need
to see
the other
summary.
This is
kind of
like,
you guys
aren't as
far from
Pennsylvania.
Anyone
you're
old enough
to have
been the
Tenwood
amusement
park?
Ah,
we got
a few.
Remember
to get
on the
ride?
There was
a holiday
duty and
the last
few matched
up to
holiday
duty and
you didn't
get on
the ride.
Very
bound to
set.
Very
bound to
set.
Okay,
Rupert
noticed this
is another
way to look
at it and
it's what
he called
the
strength
set.
And in
this
context,
in the
sense of
set,
the
question
is
really
only
two
things.
What is
your
direction
and is
there any
movement?
You see,
in the
bound to
set,
if I go to
church Sunday
morning,
Sunday night,
and Wednesday
night,
I die,
I don't
smoke,
and I don't
chew,
I can be an
elder.
It don't
matter that I'm a
biggie,
that's fine.
Because that's
not part of
the bound
itself.
Okay?
So,
for Jesus
in
terrible,
the person
who ended
up justified
was not
the guy
who fit
in the
bound
itself
to check
off all
the boxes,
the Pharisees,
rather the
person that
he said
walks away
justified
is the
guy who's
so far
away,
he's that
guy way
out there,
he can't
even get
close.
So,
the value
of the
virtues
of Jesus,
he even
becomes
the
sanctuary,
as he
was moving
toward
God.
He recognized
that I was
so sleeping
for him,
but he was
moving.
And with
that same
day,
it comes
into much
more of the
unique thing
than his
other thing.
I don't
know about
you,
but one of
my sisters
had already
grown up
to you too
for 40
years.
I mean,
they got
their first
two years
done,
they did
really well,
and they
got burnt
by someone
of some
things,
and they
keep doing
the first
things,
but you
gotta ask,
so what's
your relationship
like with
Jesus?
Don't we
believe that
it's about
a relationship
with Jesus?
I mean,
don't we
believe that?
Isn't that
important?
A relationship
is about
it's about
direction
and momentum.
You can
also have
people who
are actually
really close
to going
the wrong
way.
And that's
a problem.
And so
Peter said
that the
Indians
used what
he called
to fight
the fight
the fight.
It's
when you
pointed
toward
Jesus
and
the
Indian.
And
again,
if any
time you
take
an example
rightfully
and you
make
this
standard,
this by
itself
becomes
insufficient,
and that's
what people
said back
to being
Carson.
You know,
everything you're
saying is
right,
Carson,
except it's
right if I'm
an angel
to tell them
because they
need to hear
what you're
saying,
because the
Americans
don't need
to hear
any more
of that.
They need
to hear
that,
get over
your
boundaries
that you
create,
to keep
people out
and defy
who's
in the
next,
and then
it's
the
people.
God
cares about
momentum
and
direction.
Don't
forgive him.
I think
that's
very
helpful
when we
talk about
expectations.
I think
it's
helpful.
First of all,
I'm going to
go through
a few more
verses
because
I'm
assuming
that most
of you
have
started
on this
journey
and you're
on the
journey
and
praise
God.
I'm
pretty
sure
that's
true
because
worship
was
so
good.
I mean,
it's just
kind of
the indicator.
But I
also think
that because
some of us
here,
maybe it's
just for me,
maybe you're
wondering,
do you remember
the old
Christ
that put
salvation
like a
thing?
in this
tract,
you know,
the angel
was the
head
and
doctrine
knowing
and
you know,
they're done
the same.
And they
acknowledge
feelings,
the feelings
were always
the caduce.
Feelings of
father.
And I
don't
understand why
they say that.
I can't get
that.
We can't be
controlled by
our feelings.
But in my
experience,
most people
come to the
sentence this
way.
actually,
the feelings
aren't at the
boast.
The feelings
are like the
coals thrown
in the
angel.
Jesus talks
about God
re-starting.
You know,
I have this
recognition
that I'm
broken.
I have this
recognition
that I'm
lost.
I have this
recognition
that I'm
a sinner.
I can't.
It's kind
of like the
those of you
who are
familiar with
AA's,
you know,
step 1,
2,
and 3.
It really
paralyzes
often.
I can't.
And they
use words,
I'm powerless,
blah, blah, blah.
I can't.
But there's
someone who
can.
There's a
higher power
that can
restore
insanity.
And step
free,
I'm going
to run.
to yield.
What do
we think
about yielding
our life?
That we
yield our
lives to
them.
God
is for
us.
He brings
the pity.
And according
to this
passage,
that repentance
leads to
salvation.
And when
it's done
well,
it leaves
no regrets.
A feeling,
a conviction,
a change of
intention to
salvation with
no regrets.
This is 1 John
1, 9.
If we confess
our sins,
He is faithful
and just to
forgive us our
sins.
and you
conjure
from all
unrighteousness.
I mean,
you're pure.
You're pure.
You're clean.
Has anyone
here, like,
been four or five
days in the
woods without
selling?
What's the
first thing you
do when you
get that
vaccine?
My wife and
I took two
weeks,
which is a
while ago,
hiking the
first thing in
Yellowstone.
And the only
balance we
got was in
Lake Yellowstone,
which is about
36 degrees.
Bouts were
very quick.
And we didn't
take enough
salt.
And when we
got out,
we did two
things.
I got a
hamburger,
and I took
the salt,
and I made
the whole
top of you
and I'm
going to
go white
because I
feel free of
salt.
It has
nothing to do
with what I'm
preaching.
But the
second thing
we did was
we paid a
couple bucks
for a
sour.
They gave
me a
whole big
bar of
soap,
and I
soured
until that
whole bar
of soap
was gone.
Hot water,
yeah.
I mean,
what a
cream.
It's
just an
other
match.
Folks,
God and
sour
is good.
It's
great.
good.
It's
a
gift.
The
danger
of
honestly,
that
world
is
solemn.
The
fire
distanced
through
countries
is not
friendly,
and it's
not
good.
That's
exciting
and has
two
ways.
One,
to get
you to
ignore
all
people
of
guilt
and
sorry
just
ignore
them.
Cover
them
over,
and you
hundred
different
ways.
All
kind
of
change
that
you
can
take
to
just
ignore
it.
If you
can't
get you
to do
that,
then you
want you
to live
in your
silence.
Because it
makes you
inflective.
So if you're
forgiving,
you're
forgiving.
You're
not
just
forgiving,
but you're
clanged.
And you're
not just
clanged from
lachity,
you're
clanged from
all
unrighteousness.
All
Okay,
another
one.
So this
is the
passage
which we
get a
minute in
canvas
and some
words
in here.
You almost
can't talk
about salvation
without
dealing with
this passage.
It's just
a great
passage.
And it
gives kind of
the whole
picture here
in a
wonderful,
wonderful
way.
For by
grace,
you'd be
saved.
You know,
you're not
saved by
faith.
You're
saved by
grace.
It's
through
faith.
Faith is
the agency
of God's
active
salvation,
but it's
the grace
of God
that saves
us.
The grace
is activated
through
faith.
It's
not
in the
faith.
We
can't
do it.
We
can't
walk it
up.
We
can't
be a
good
enough
Pharisee
to
say,
I'm
glad I'm
not like
him.
Because I'm
not going to
then walk
into the
presence of
the Lord
just to
face.
No,
I start,
Lord,
I don't
for you.
You're
good.
Thank you.
Forgive me.
Have
mercy on
me.
And
with this
wonderful
reception.
for
by
grace
you
have
been
saved
from
faith
and
that's
not
of
yourself.
It's
the
gift
of
God.
It's
a
lot of
gifts.
Not a
result of
life.
No one
can do
it.
And then
verse
20.
For we
are his
enemies.
We're his
workmanship.
poemas.
We're his
creative
action.
Created
in
Christ
Jesus
for
good
works
which
God
prepared
before
mind
that
we
should
walk
in.
William
Barclay
says,
here is
the
calling
paradise.
All the
good
works in
the world
cannot put
us right
with God.
But there
is something
rightfully
wrong with
the salvation
that doesn't
produce good
works.
Salvation
It
changes
you.
It
changes
you.
you meet
Jesus
and he
doesn't
just
infuse
but he
impart
righteousness
to you.
Those are
two big
words.
We can
talk about
those
right
if you
want.
Okay.
Here's my
line of
phrase.
And
I'm using
it specifically
because
we're going
to end
the message
in just
a little
bit.
But we're
going to
continue
the message
through
the
dramatic
act.
And the
dramatic
act
is going
to be
baptism.
And here
we actually
practice
baptism,
the mode
of baptism
in a few
different ways.
And of course
I'd be happy
to do a few
more.
If I was
someone who
could not
go under
the water,
I would
spring.
Maybe that's
here to see
you.
I don't
know.
But in
the early
church,
they actually
have artwork
that shows
running
water.
when they
would
immerse,
at least
according to
this artwork,
it was
at a
waterfall,
and so
they would
immerse
you under
the water
that was
pouring
over you.
How about that
in this
tool?
Well,
the two
images we
use here,
once it's
ten times
forward,
once it's
once backwards,
because these
two both
get at the
double aspect
of this
verse.
Paul told us
in chapter
10,
verse 9,
and then he
reiterated in
verse 10,
for if you
confess with
your mouth
Jesus as
Lord,
in other
words,
if you
recognize
that he's
the boss,
and we
don't use
the word
Lord a lot,
but if you
recognize
that he's
the boss,
you submit
to him,
you recognize
his exalted
position in
your life,
and that's
why we
that good
some people
think I'm
born in
the name
of the
Father,
in the name
of the
Son,
in the name
of the
Holy Spirit,
because we
balance the
mission before
God in
this
salvific
position.
You know
I'm sorry.
I was in
charge.
I did a
pretty big
job.
Time for
you to
poke
over the
roof.
That's
a song.
How come
when I do
like top
culture stuff,
you guys all
get it.
go through
the video,
Leo takes
the reel,
because
someone on
the boat
needs to
study.
Again,
nothing to do
with this
message.
Good
word,
you're aware
of glory
when you're
young.
So,
if you
confess with
your mouth
Jesus as
Lord,
and here's
the second
part,
and believe
in your
heart that
God raised
him from
the death,
that is
a phrase
that takes
from the
whole
crucifixion,
resurrection,
an ascension
paradigm,
that he
did it,
he purchased
your salvation,
he did
what's
necessary,
he wants
to apply
to you
what is
necessary,
because he
loves you,
he loves you
just the way
you are,
you don't
want to
stay just
the way
you are.
and so
died and
rose and
provided
ultimate
forgiveness
so that
you can
actually
walk in
righteousness.
Wow,
what a
wonderful
thing.
And so
we've got
to have
people
backwards
saying,
you know,
guide that
old person
and you're
raised to
tell them
with Christ
you're alive
and home.
What a
great image.
I love
it.
And I
think about
that's
the reason
I'm going
to do
this.
By
the way,
in a little
bit,
if you
have not
followed the
Lord and
wanted
to
do
it,
the
biblical
precedent
is
the
sea
water
that's
doing it.
And so
if anyone
wants to
follow the
Lord,
we have
like six
or seven
piles over
here,
and only two
people getting
baptized,
they know
you don't
get one
from your
hair and
one from
your body,
just one
towel.
So we
have towels
for plenty.
Now,
by the way,
if you're a
child and
you want
to get
baptized,
you need
to talk
to your
child.
We just
think that's
important.
We think
kind of
like,
parents have
your first
pastor
and your
primary
pastor.
So we
want them
involved in
that process.
Okay.
So,
three times
forward,
your Lord
wants
backwards,
and you
dignified
what you
did.
And
it's not
in the
sense.
It's not
in the
sense.
Okay.
Let me
end this
message by
giving four
things,
and you'll
remember it
because it
sticks with
four of these
great
teaching things.
And I
wish,
don't
know I
wish,
and you'll
remember it.
Okay.
You're saved
from the wrath
of God
to total
forgiveness.
Salvation is
not just what
you're saved
from,
but it's
also what
you're saved
to.
And so,
you're saved
from the wrath
of God
to total
forgiveness.
You're also
saved from
isolation from
God to a new
life from
Christ.
And by the
way,
this isolation
from God,
it often
manifests itself
in isolation
from others
as well.
I don't know
about you,
but I remember
my college days
before I was
a Christian,
I can remember
standing in a
pastor dorm room
where I could
not walk
holding my beer.
If I moved
to the right
or the left,
I was going to
throw it on me
and someone else.
And I was
so freaking
out of the way.
He was a
people,
but no
real connection.
it's when
you enter
into Christ,
it gives you
an automatic
connection with
your God.
I don't
understand it,
but when two
Christians put
a cross to
each other,
turn your
cards to
each other,
and share
authentically
something,
we can
trust it.
It's why we
do small
groups,
it's why we
do men's
gifts,
it's why we
do energy
treats,
it's why we
do more
than just
sit here and
look at the
back to
someone
celebrating
him and
sanctificate
it.
Because there's
something about
two Christians
who actually
in their
fantasy,
unbelieving
in the
fantasy.
So it
moves us
through selfish
pursuits
to a
grand
purpose.
I don't
know about
you,
but I
want to
make a
difference.
And there's
nothing in
a plan of
here like
serving the
Lord of
Jesus to
make a
difference.
nothing
else to
celebrate.
Nothing.
And last
of all,
sin is
an awful,
awful
ministry.
But there's
a harsh
dominion of
sin and
it's why
these
spirits and
godly
sparkles.
Guilt is
debilitating.
Shame is
salvation is
delivering you
from that
harsh
dominion of
sin to
freedom in
spirit.
For anyone
here who is
sick and
tired,
tired.
If you've
never said
yes to
Jesus,
Jesus
used to
him.
If you've
said yes to
Jesus,
if you've
been living
in the
bound itself,
maybe you
need to
step into
the center
center.
You can
move forward
here.
And if
you're
waiting out
here,
because you're
just moving
on at
least.
She'll
take it.
Why?
Because you
don't.
Can you
love you
just the way
you are?
There's too
much to
be doing
for you.
See,
I'll see you
back.
So we
know,
months and
a half
we're
going to
invite
people
to
send
our
success
to
a
personal
experience
of
God's
saving
race
in my
life
and
the
help
of
the
Holy Spirit
and
the
Holy Spirit
where the
whole
lives
devoted
to the
example
and the
spirit of
Christ.
We're
going to
display
that
in
church.
Some
little
kids,
some
kids are
going to be
coming in.
I'm going to
take up this
spot.
I'm going to
see if
you're
getting
back
there.
I think
Leah's
already
over a
great
rejoice
with
each
place.
Are you
going to
anyone?
Anyone
want to
say
anything?
I want to
do it.
I don't
know.
You're
welcome to
come.